katywidrick.com 2016-09-13

# Policies » Katy Widrick

**KatyWidrick.com (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy and disclosure Policy (updated April  2016).**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website. This Website may contain third-party links to other websites which are not governed by this policy. 

**What Information Do We Collect and How Is This Information Used?**

  1. We may receive and store information that you voluntarily submit through the Website for the purpose of subscribing to the Website to receive newsletters, for the purpose of leaving comments on blog posts, or administering sweepstakes, contests or promotions. Examples of information collected for this purpose are your name, email address and website URL. This information is only captured when you voluntarily enter or opt-in and enter this information for collection. 
  2. We may receive and store certain types of usage-related information when you interact with the Website, including but not limited to, your computer’s IP address and browser information. The information we collect is used to customize the content and/or layout of our page for each individual visitor. 
  3. We use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personal information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.
  4. The Website uses Google Analytics to track statistics regarding our audience and Website traffic. No personally identifiable information is transferred from the Website to Google Analytics. [For more information on Google’s Analytics privacy policies, please visit this site](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). 
  5. This Website engages in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.
  6. The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described above. 
  7. KatyWidrick.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales. 

**Third-Party Use of Personal Information**

The Website may provide personal information to an applicable third party in order to provide services. Currently, the Website uses the services of MailChimp for delivery of email updates and newsletters. MailChimp‘s use of your personal information is subject to MailChimp‘s privacy policy. 

Your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. 

Information that does not identify you personally may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

**Will We Share the Personal Information It Collects?**

We will not sell, distribute, or reveal users’ email addresses or other personal information without their consent. This does not include third-party partners, such as those listed above. 

**Modification or Deletion of Personal Information**

You can decline to submit personal information at any time. If you decline, we may not be able to continue to provide service to you. You may request deletion of your personal information by sending an email to kwidrick@gmail.com, but in some cases, we may be required to keep your information by law. In such a case, it would no longer be active and would be kept separately in an archive.

**Disclosures:**

As a lover of all things healthy and fun, I often review products and events, not only for my own research, but to share my opinions with others. They are just that — opinions.

From time to time, companies will send me products to try, free of cost. Also, when I compete at events (triathlons, races, etc) I often receive free samples of foods, drinks or other products.

**Whenever I review or refer to a product that was provided to me, I will make it clear in the post.** I provide not only details of how I received the product, but I often link to the company itself. My reviews are honest, and if _ _ done at the request of a company, rest assured that the compensation of cash or product does not have any bearing on the content. If I do not like a product, I will either not review it on the blog, or I will state the reasons why I don’t like it.

_If I purchased the product, I will not necessarily state that in the post._

**From time to time, I do accept sponsored posts, for which I am paid in cash or other compensation.** When I do that, I make it clear in the post and include a link to this policy.

**As stated above, I also do use affiliate links and banners across my website.  **While I always try to make it as clear as possible, it is possible that when you click a link or a banner on my site, I may get a small commission or other compensation. The only things you’ll see me link to or recommend are products or services I’ve tried or used myself, and if you choose to click through but prefer not to use my affiliate tag, simply remove that from the web address before completing your purchase.

Also — please note that I work part-time for a company called Growing Bolder, also known as Bolder Media Group or Bolder Broadcasting, Inc. Often, I will post links to stories that my company has helped produce. When I do, I will attempt to make that clear but am not ever _paid  _to share my professional content on my personal blog or social networks.

Additionally, I run a blog coaching and consulting service called [Make Me{dia} Over](http://makemediaover.com/). From time to time, I will advertise my services here on this website.

**Questions?** Please e-mail me (kwidrick@gmail.com) or refer to the FTC’s ruling on blogger disclosure:

_**For disclosure outside of my blog:**_

  * #AD or #sponsored: denotes that a brand has compensated me in some way for the post or message — in most cases, the message will be in my own words but may also include copy points from the client. This compensation may have been in cash or in product.

When I don’t use the #AD or #sponsored tags, I follow FTC guidelines by using clear language to let you know that something is sponsored.
